

□+34634491616 | ≥ sebastian.daza@gmail.com | ★ sdaza.com | □ sdaza | □ sdaza

# **Summary**\_

I am a senior data scientist and analyst with practical experience designing, managing, supervising, and analyzing applied industry and social studies. I possess strong quantitative and qualitative skills, as well as a background in health, social, and behavioral sciences. I am excited to apply my knowledge and skills to research and influence people, and I enjoy working with interdisciplinary and multicultural teams.

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

**Teladoc (Telemedicine)** 

SENIOR DATA SCIENTIST Apr 2023 - Present

- Technical lead in data science, personalization, and causal inference (internal workshops and technical guidance)
- · Led uplift modeling and incrementality testing of media campaigns with geo-experiments and A/B tests
- Created experiment and causal inference package for imbalance adjustment (IPW, IV), meta-analysis, and power analysis
- Developed a multi-touch attribution (MTA) model to evaluate investments in paid media and optimize spending
- Developed a life time value (LTV) model that helps inform marketing investments for optimal results
- · Create LLM pipeline with Azure OpenAI to extract information from doctors' notes and content generation
- Created tools to process data efficiently with PySpark and Databricks (e.g., internal Python packages, CICD pipelines, Terraform)
- Automated the generation of metrics using PySpark
- Created Tableau dashboards that provide insights to stakeholders

## **Lookiero (Online Personal Styling Service)**

Remote, Spain

Jun 2022 - Feb 2023

SENIOR DATA SCIENTIST

- Technical lead in data science and causal inference (internal workshops and technical guidance)
- Used statistical models to identify sources of product success (variance decomposition)
- Causal estimation of discount strategies. Simulation of scenarios. Increased the contribution margin more than 5%
- Developed a hybrid recommendation model using more than 200M feedbacks from users
- · Contributed to define a framework to iterate neural network models in Databricks (PySpark), decreasing time in training

#### Institute of Economy, Geography and Demography, CCSH-CSIC

Madrid, Spain

SENIOR DATA RESEARCHER ANALYST

Dec 2019 - Apr 2022

- · Led a team of researchers to study early conditions, delayed adult effects and morbidity, disability, and mortality
- Led Scrum ceremonies and tracked progress using Notion
- Authorship of 5+ academic papers and presentations in conferences
- · Supervised and implemented complex data analysis on demography and genomics using R and Java
- Health modeling and simulation using Anylogic

## Juntos Global (Conversational technology platform for financial users)

May 2018 - Dec 2019

DATA SCIENTIST

• Led analytic and data science team for banking user insights

- Provided user insights through the design and analysis of experiments (A/B testing), improving banks' engagement
- · Implemented NLP and machine learning models to classify banking users and topics and help to resolve their needs
- · Worked closely with Product Managers, Software Engineers, and Design team to improve Juntos' banking engagement product
- Collaborated in the design and implementation of the data pipeline using Python, PySpark, and Databricks

#### Center for Studies in Demography and Ecology, UW-Madison

Madison, US

Jul 2014 - May 2018 RESEARCH ASSISTANT

- · Communicated insights to different audiences in 5+ empirical research papers, and 10+ presentations at scientific conferences
- Led all aspects of 5+ research studies (funding, design, analysis, reporting)

#### **Center for Social Studies, Catholic University**

Guatemala, Mexico and Peru, and 10,000 cases

RESEARCH DIRECTOR

May 2005 - Jul 2010 · Led several research projects in areas such as organizational studies (engagement surveys and culture analysis), political perception and govern-

ment approval ratings, education (curriculum impact), tobacco and substance, and crime and delinquency • A key project was the Survey of Social Cohesion in Latin America(ECosociaL) that involved 7 countries: Chile, Argentina, Brazil, Colombia,

DECEMBER 29, 2024 SEBASTIAN DAZA · RÉSUMÉ 1

# **Consulting**

Kreuger Consulting, LLC Texas, U.

DATA SCIENTIST May. 2021 - Jul. 2021

- · Created an interactive data dashboard tool using R and Shiny, to visualize the output of a Covid-19 agent-based model
- · Provided domain stakeholders with the ability to interact with and modify the results displayed

Personio Madrid, Spain

**DATA SCIENTIST**May. 2020 - Jul. 2020

- · Created an interactive data dashboard tool using R and Shiny to assess recruitment performance and transition rates between interview states.
- The dashboard also simulates hiring scenarios to estimate the number of interviews and recruiters needed by position, role, and office.
- It improved the detection of bottlenecks and assessment of performance.

#### **Applied Population Lab, UW-Madison**

Madison, US

Oct. 2016 - Jul. 2018

- Created R package to extract variables and statistics from the American Community Survey and Decennial US Census.
- The package automatized the extraction of data and improved the time for reporting.

#### **Center for Social Studies, Catholic University**

Santiago, Chile

Jul. 2010 - May. 2018

- Designed samples and post-adjustments in large studies (organizational, public opinion, and educational studies)
- Provided methodological guidance (attrition, non-response adjustment)

## **Skills**

DATA SCIENTIST

DATA SCIENTIST

**Programming** Python, R, Java

Data science ML, DL (Keras), Visualization (Dash, Shiny), PySpark, Petastorm, SQL, Redshift, PostgreSQL, Databricks

Stats/modeling Experimentation (AB testing), causal inference, hierarchical modeling, survival analysis, Bayesian statistics, simulation, agent-based

modeling (ABM)

**Survey design** Sample design, weighting, non-response adjustments, bias analysis, technical reporting, methodological evaluation

**Tools** Notion, Trello, Jira, Confluence, Git, Latex

Languages English, Spanish

**Teaching** Prepared course materials on statistics and modeling, and provided feedback for over 200 students.

## Software

**experiment-utils** Python package for analysis and design of experiments

acsr R package to extract variables and statistics from the American Community Survey and Decennial US Census

**zotnote** Python package to extract notes from Zotero (Reference Manager)

# Education\_

#### **University of Wisconsin-Madison**

Madison, US

PhD in Demography and Sociology

The Data Incubator Washington DC, US

DATA SCIENCE PROGRAM

#### **Catholic University of Chile**

Santiago Chile

MASTER OF ARTS IN SOCIOLOGY

December 29, 2024 Sebastian Daza · Résumé 2